Jaikishan Patel

Visual Communication Designer

jaiksworld@gmail.com www.jaiki.in

Love to Observe, Experience & Design. Focused in Communication Design, believing if there is an honest communication, Life can be understood very easily.

Love to observe how various communication happens around. Respect the value addition and attention to details. Highly concerned about the brand language and its behavior.

Born and brought up at Raigarh in the region of Chhattisgarh INDIA. Studied Visual Communication at Industrial Design Centre, IIT-Bombay, Mumbai. Previously, completed undergraduate studies from the department of Communication Design at DJ Academy of Design, Coimbatore in 2011.

Work Experience in Design

2015-Present | Visual Designer

Directi Groups Mumbai, India

Working on User Interface and brand language for the Media.net, global advertising technology firm based in India. Responsibilities include development and implementation of a consistent visual language across multiple products owned by Directi.

Media.net:

- ~ User interface design for Data Monetization interfaces
- ~ Visualization for Data Analysis Layout, Time Series and Statistical Analysis
- ~ Visual language for native search engine by Media.net
- ~ Visualization and User interface design for Mail Tech interfaces
- ~ Visual designs for custom web extensions

2015 | Sr. Project Assistant

Industrial Design Centre, IIT Bombay, Mumbai, India

Extensions of Mumbai Rail Map Project under the Mumbai Transformation Project: Design, implementation & documentation of YRH Backlit Maps in Hindi, Marathi & English at Western Railway Stations (Bandra and Dadar). Design and implementation of the Mobile Application (MrmApp) for iOS and Android

2013-2015 | TA (Teaching Assistant)

Industrial Design Centre, IIT Bombay, Mumbai, India

Mumbai Rail Map (MRM): Design of the Mumbai Rail Map in 5 Languages; Hindi, Marathi, English, Gujarati and Urdu. Documentation of user feedback at Central Railway Stations (Dadar and Mumbai CST). MrmApp: Design of the Travel application for the Mumbai sub-urban rail network

2012-13 | Senior Visualizer

Marching Ants Advertising Mumbai, India

Corporate - Identity & Visual Design:

Fun Cinemas, ONLY, Varamoda, Jack & Jones, Aries, Touchworks, African Wildlife Trust, Provogue

Films - Identity & Visual Design:

Aiyaa, Special 26, Go Goa Gone, Inkaar, 2 States, Bheru, Rum Pum Posshh, Ek Thi Daayan, Shootout at Wadala, Bhaag Milkha Bhaag, Queen, Ranjhana, Roy, Bombay Velvet

2011-12 | Graphic Designer

Afresh Thinking Design Bengaluru, India

Identity - Premier League 2012 Cable & Wireless Worldwide, Bengaluru Interior & Environmental graphics - Silvertips The Silvertips groups of hotels, Munnar, Kerala Identity, Online media - Rural Foundation Rural Foundation, Mangalore

2011 | Design Project

Haier telecommunication Gurgaon, India

Visual Brand Language - Olive telecom Olive telecommunication pvt. Ltd., India User Interface, Icon Design - Skylink Mobile Skylink telecom, Russia Visual Identity - R&D Center (Q Innovations) Qualcomm / Olive telecom

2010 | Design Intern

The Leaf Design Pvt. Ltd. Mumbai, India

The very first experience of working for real time projects with a team from various departments together Environmental Graphics - Fountainhead Learning Centre Edelweiss corporation, Alibaug, Mumbai

Educational Qualifications

2013-2015 | Post Graduation in Visual Communication

Industrial Design Centre, IIT Bombay, Mumbai (MH) India

Specialisation programme in Visual Communication: Visual Design & Communication theories, study and practices with live projects.

2007-II | Undergraduation in Communication Design

D J Academy of Design Coimbatore (TN) India

Undergraduate Program in Design: One year of foundation, with opportunities for exploration of Design Process and various skills related to design. Three years of expertise in communication design

2002-04 | Higher Secondary

Saraswati Hr. Sec. School, Raigarh (CG) India

Physics, Chemistry, Maths & Biology

Key Skills

Languages

Hindi, English

Design basics

Visualization, Sketching, Drawing, Concept art and Visual Scripting, User study & Research oriented Analysis, Understanding of Visual Culture & formal aesthetics, Print & Digital Graphics, Video editing

Tools

Software - Adobe InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Final Cut Pro

Personal information

Gender - Male | Birth - 15th June 1986, Raigarh (Chhattisgarh), India | Father's Name - Hiralal Patel | Mother's Name - Yashoda Patel | Nationality - Indian | Identity - Passport Number: Z3384302 | Identity - National Driving Licence : J-128-2005

Personal Interest:

Travelling to new localities, Cricket & other outdoor sports

Exposures in Communication Design

Elements of Communication Design:

Form & Space, Colour, Contrast, Composition, Visual Hierarchy, Typography, Printing Technology, Publication Design, Illustration, Packaging Design

Visual culture, Brand Language:

Visual Identity, Environmental Graphics, Developmental Communication, Photography, Interactive Media, Visual merchandising, Advertising, Publicity Design

Film Language:

Character design, Visual scripting and storyboarding, Elements of film, Film and Video theory and structure, Basic 2D animation